Dr. Chuanxia Zheng

Research Interests

His research interests focus on computer vision and machine learning, especially for generative AI. He has done a wide range of work on 2D and 3D scene synthesis, with the goal of synthesizing a photorealistic virtual world via generative AI. In particular, on topics:

- 3D geometry and appearance from limited views or videos.
- 3D editing via object-centric perception.
- Generative models for physical world understanding.
- Multi-modalities (1D, 2D, 3D, and 4D) generation and understanding.

Professional experience

2022-now Postdoctoral Research Fellow, University of Oxford, UK.

2D and 3D scene synthesis

2021–2022 Research Fellow, Monash University, Australia.

Codebook learning for 2D and 3D synthesis

Education

2017–2021 Doctor of Philosophy (PhD).

Nanyang Technological University

School of Computer Science and Engineering, Singapore

Thesis: Synthesizing Photorealistic Images with Deep Generative Learning Outstanding PhD Thesis Award, Advisors: Tat-Jen Cham and Jianfei Cai

2014–2017 Master of Science (MSc) in computer science.

Beihang University, Beijing, China

Thesis: Context-based Indoor Scene Understanding for Mobile Robot

Advisors: Jianhua Wang and Weihai Chen

2010–2014 Bachelor of Science in information engineering.

 $Beijing\ Jiaotong\ University,$ Beijing, China

Thesis: Image Retrieval based on Visual Saliency

Highest Honours (Outstanding Graduate of Beijing), Advisor: Ze Liu

Research Experience

2022-now Postdoc, University of Oxford, UK, Prof. Andrea Vedaldi.

Research interests: 3D reconstruction from limited images or videos

Four papers accepted by ICML(1), ICCV(1), NeurIPS(1), ICLR(1)

2021-2022 Cooperator, The national AI research Lab of Vietnam, Vietnam, Dr. Hung Bui.

Research interests: high-quality image generation and data compression

Three papers accepted by NeurIPS(1), ICLR(1), ICML(1)

2021-2022 Research Fellow, Monash University, Australia, Prof. Jianfei cai.

Research interests: nature scene generation and completion

Three papers accepted by CVPR(1), ECCV(2)

2017-2021 PhD, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore, Prof. Nadia Thalmann.

Research interests: photorealistic image generation

Seven papers accepted by CVPR(2), ECCV(1), ICCV(1), SIGGRAPH(1) and IJCV(2)

Awards and other recognitions

- 2023 Outstanding Reviewer Award, Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)
- 2022 Scholar/Travel Award, Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)
- 2022 Presidential Postdoctoral Fellowship (PPF), Nanyang Technological University, Singapore
- 2022 Outstanding PhD Thesis Award, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore
- 2021 Outstanding Reviewer Award, IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM)
- 2017 NTU Research Scholarship
- 2014 Outstanding Graduate of Beijing
- 2013 National Prize of the National Electronic Design Contest of China (Best in Beijing)
- 2012 Hanergy Scholarship Award (**Top 1%**)
- 2011 Siemens Scholarship Award (**Top 1%**)

Press Coverage

- 2023 Sber.ru: MoVQ 0.1 means a lot for text-image generation Kandinsky 2.1 (Github: 2.3K)
- 2022 Phys.org: Researchers unravel cell biology through artificial intelligence
- 2022 NTU News: NTU SCSE Outstanding PhD Thesis Award 2022
- 2022 Zhuanzhi: How to create photorealistic images? Ph.D. Thesis by Dr. Zheng
- 2021 kknews, Sohu, NetEase: AgileGAN a tool for creating stylized portraits (Demo: 10K/week)

Service to the academic community

- Reviewer for international journals. IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (**TPAMI**), International Journal on Computer Vision (**IJCV**), IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (**TIP**), IEEE Transactions on Multimedia(**TMM**), Computer Vision and Image Understanding (**CVIU**), The Visual Computer (**TVC**).
- Reviewer for international conferences. IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) 2020-2024, European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) 2020, 2022, 2024 International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2019, 2021, 2023, International Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) 2022-2023, International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) 2021-2023, International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2023, International Conference on Computer Graphics (SIGGRAPH) 2021,2022, International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) 2023.

International workshops

2024 "Second Workshop for Learning 3D with Multi-View Supervision" at the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (**CVPR**) with Abdullah Hamdi, Silvio Giancola, Guocheng Qian, Jinjie Mai, Sara Rojas Martinez, Bernard S. Ghanem, and Yash Bhalgat.

Mentoring and student supervision

PhD

- 2023- Ruining Li, University of Oxford, co-supervised with Prof. Andrea Vedaldi
- 2023- Zeyu Wang, Nanyang Technological University, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham
- 2023- Fengming Liu, Nanyang Technological University, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham
- 2023- Tianhao Wu, Nanyang Technological University, co-supervised with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham
- 2022-2023 Minghui Hu, Nanyang Technological University, co-supervised for three terms with Prof. Tat-Jen Cham
 - 2021- Yuedong Chen, Monash University, co-supervised with Prof. Jianfei Cai

Master

- 2024- Wenbo Ji, Technical University of Munich (TUM), Projects for summer semester 2024, cosupervised with Dr. Yan Xia and Prof. Daniel Cremers
- 2023- Jingbo Zhao, University of Oxford, Undergraduate Part B extend Essay

Teaching

- 2023-2023 **Teaching Assistant**, B16: Software Engineering, Undergraduate, University of Oxford.
- 2023-2023 **Teaching**, Generative AI, Graduate, University of Oxford.
- 2018–2020 Teaching Assistant, Advanced Digital Image Processing, Graduate, NTU.
- 2018–2020 Teaching Assistant, Human-Computer Interaction, Undergraduate, NTU.
- 2018–2019 Teaching Assistant, Engineering Mathematics, Undergraduate, NTU.

Invited talks

- 2023 Visiting the Invisible via Generative AI, University of Science and Technology, China.
- 2023 Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Harbin Institute of Technology, China.
- 2023 Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore, NTU.
- 2023 Codebook Leaning for Generative AI, University of Oxford, UK.
- 2022 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore, Link.
- 2022 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, University of Oxford, UK.
- 2022 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, ETH, Zürich.
- 2022 Synthesizing Photorealistic Scenes, University of Science and Technology, China.
- 2019 Pluralistic Image Completion, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore.
- 2018 Depth Estimation from Single 2D Image, Nanyang Technological University, Singapore.

Publications

- [22] Tianhao Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Panodiffusion: 360-degree panorama outpainting via diffusion. In *The Eleventh International Conference on Learning Representations* (*ICLR*), 2024. URL: https://sm0kywu.github.io/panodiffusion/.
- [21] Minghui Hu, Jianbin Zheng, Daqing Liu, Chuanxia Zheng, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Tat-Jen Cham. Cocktail: Mixing multi-modality control for text-conditional image generation. In Thirty-seventh Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2023. URL: https://mhh0318.github.io/cocktail/.
- [20] Chuanxia Zheng and Andrea Vedaldi. Online clustered codebook. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision(ICCV)*, 2023. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/cvq/.
- [19] Long Tung Vuong, Trung Le, He Zhao, Chuanxia Zheng, Mehrtash Harandi, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Vector quantized wasserstein auto-encoder. In The Fortieth International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML), 2023.
- [18] Minghui Hu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Heliang Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Zuopeng Yang, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Ponnuthurai N. Suganthan. Unified discrete diffusion for simultaneous vision-language generation. In *The Eleventh International Conference on Learning Representations* (*ICLR*), 2023. URL: https://mhh0318.github.io/unid3/.
- [17] Chuanxia Zheng, Long Tung Vuong, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Movq: Modulating quantized vectors for high-fidelity image generation. In *Thirty-sixth Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS)*, 2022. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/movq/.

- [16] Jyothsna Vasudevan*, Chuanxia Zheng*, James G. Wan, Tat-Jen Cham, Lim Chwee Teck, and Javier G. Fernandez. From qualitative data to correlation using deep generative networks: Demonstrating the relation of nuclear position with the arrangement of actin filaments. *PloS one*, 17(7):e0271056, 2022.
- [15] Qianyi Wu, Xian Liu, Yuedong Chen, Kejie Li, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianfei Cai, and Jianming Zheng. Object-compositional neural implicit surfaces. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision* (**ECCV**), 2022. URL: https://wuqianyi.top/objectsdf/.
- [14] Yuedong Chen, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Sem2nerf: Converting single-view semantic masks to neural radiance fields. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2022. URL: https://donydchen.github.io/sem2nerf/.
- [13] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, and Dinh Phung. Bridging global context interactions for high-fidelity image completion. In *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR)*, pages 11512–11522, June 2022. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/tfill/.
- [12] Chuanxia Zheng, Duy-Son Dao, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Visiting the invisible: Layer-by-layer completed scene decomposition. *International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV)*, 129(12):3195–3215, 2021. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/vinv/.
- [11] Yujun Cai, Yiwei Wang, Yiheng Zhu, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Junsong Yuan, Jun Liu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Sijie Yan, Henghui Ding, Xiaohui Shen, Ding Liu, and Nadia Magnenat Thalmann. A unified 3d human motion synthesis model via conditional variational auto-encoder. In *Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision*(*ICCV*), pages 11645–11655, 2021.
- [10] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic free-form image completion. International Journal of Computer Vision (IJCV), 129(10):2786–2805, 2021. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/pic/.
- [9] Guoxian Song, Linjie Luo, Jing Liu, Wan-Chun Ma, Chunpong Lai, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. Agilegan: stylizing portraits by inversion-consistent transfer learning. *ACM Transactions on Graphics* (*TOG*), 40(4):1–13, 2021. URL: https://guoxiansong.github.io.
- [8] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. The spatially-correlative loss for various image translation tasks. In *Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition(CVPR)*, pages 16407–16417, 2021. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/flsesim/.
- [7] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Pluralistic image completion. In *Proceedings* of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), pages 1438–1447, 2019. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/pic/.
- [6] Tianyi Zhang, Jingyi Yang, Chuanxia Zheng, Guosheng Lin, Jianfei Cai, and Alex C Kot. Task-in-all domain adaptation for semantic segmentation. In 2019 IEEE Visual Communications and Image Processing (VCIP), pages 1–4. IEEE, 2019.
- [5] Chuanxia Zheng, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. T2net: Synthetic-to-realistic translation for solving single-image depth estimation tasks. In *Proceedings of the European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, pages 767–783, 2018. URL: https://chuanxiaz.com/synthetic2real/.
- [4] **Chuanxia Zheng**, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Multi-class indoor semantic segmentation with deep structured model. *The Visual Computer* (*TVCJ*), 34(5):735–747, 2018.

- [3] Jianhua Wang, Chuanxia Zheng, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning aggregated features and optimizing model for semantic labeling. The Visual Computer (TVCJ), 33(12):1587– 1600, 2017.
- [2] Chuanxia Zheng, Jianhua Wang, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Semantic segmentation based on aggregated features and contextual information. In 2016 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics (ROBIO), pages 862–867. IEEE, 2016.
- [1] Jianhua Wang, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weihai Chen, and Xingming Wu. Learning contextual information for indoor semantic segmentation. In 2016 IEEE 11th Conference on Industrial Electronics and Applications (ICIEA), pages 1639–1644. IEEE, 2016.

Preprint

- [8] Chuanxia Zheng and Andrea Vedaldi. Free3d: Consistent novel view synthesis without 3d representation. *Under reviewer*.
- [7] Minghui Hu, Jianbin Zheng, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Chaoyue Wang, Dacheng Tao, and Tat-Jen Cham. One more step: Fixing diffusion scheduler flaws without altering trained parameters.
- [6] Guanqi Zhan, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weidi Xie, and Andrew Zisserman. What does stable diffusion know about the 3d scene. *Under reviewer*.
- [5] LongTung Vuong, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Manh Luong, Thanh-Toan Do, Dinh Phung, and Trung Le. Kefi: Kernel-based feature identification for generalizable classification. *Under reviewer*.
- [4] Guanqi Zhan, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Weidi Xie, and Andrew Zisserman. Amodal completion in the wild. *Under reviewer*.
- [3] Yuedong Chen, Haofei Xu, Qianyi Wu, **Chuanxia Zheng**, Tat-Jen Cham, and Jianfei Cai. Explicit correspondence matching for generalizable neural radiance fields. *Under reviewer on* **TPAMI**.
- [2] Yuzhu Ji, **Chuanxia Zheng**, and Tat-Jen Cham. One-shot human motion transfer via occlusion-robust flow prediction and neural texturing. *Under reviewer on TNNLS*.
- [1] Chuanxia Zheng, Guoxian Song, Tat-Jen Cham, Jianfei Cai, Linjie Luo, and Dinh Phung. High-quality pluralistic image completion via code sharing. *Under reviewer on TPAMI*.